Okay thank you for watching.
Applause
What if I was to tell you that a game of peekaboo could change the world?
Sounds impossible, right?
Well, I'm here today to prove it's not.
Hi, I'm Ollie, and I'm seven, and this is my little friend Ari.
Say hi, Ari.
Hi!
Oh, and this is my neighbour.
Emma Johnson.
He has to take Ari way now to get ready for her experiment, but don't worry, they'll be back.
My talk today is about some powerful things your grown-ups can do.
They shape us as children, and the adults will become.
How do I know?
Because my parents and people around me did them early and often.
I know not all kids are as lucky.
Some of my friends, some kids at my school, and many around the world.
And I would really like to help change that.
That's the scientists!
We now know just how important the first five years are for our health and development.
Especially our brains.
Ari started learning one before he was even born from inside his mummy's tummy.
When Ari was born, she was tiny.
And he cried all the time.
He was always hungry.
And he poops a lot.
Now, he laughs and giggles and makes funny noises.
But those are just the changes we hear and see.
There's way more going on inside.
So, let's talk more about our brains.
The blue bag is a rough size and weight of a healthy baby's brainer.
The red one is a baby's brain after the first year.
It almost doubles in volume.
And by my age, it's almost 90% the volume of an adult brain.
Our brains feel faster in our early years than at any other time in our lives.
It can create up to 1 million rural connections every second.
But we need your help.
Our healthy development depends on these top five things.
One, connecting.
Two, talking.
Three, playing.
Four, a healthy home.
Five, community.
All of this helps our brains and does reach our full potential.
So, what's something you can do that can really make a difference?
Scientists call it, serve and return.
That's just a grown-up way of saying, connect, talk and play with us.
And here's the really big news.
Amajot, Ari, you ready?
Ready?
Copycat games, build imagination and empathy.
Name in games, build vocabulary and attention.
And games like peekaboo, yep, peekaboo.
Actually build memory and trust.
Each time you talk to us, play with us, make us laugh.
It not only builds and strengthens our relationships and mental health.
It actually teaches us some of the most important life skills.
From making friends, to taking the test, to getting a job to one day,
maybe even starting a family of our own.
Interactions only in optimism matter.
Take it from me, the seven-year-old up here, talking about brain science.
Okay, now let's see what happens when the connection is taken away.
So now he's trying to get his dad's attention again.
He's reaching out like, that was fun, why have you stopped?
I know it's important for adults to use their devices sometimes.
But kids are hardwired to seek out meaningful connections,
not receiving them, causes confusion and stress.
Okay, I'm a jot, please reengage.
I think...
Okay, okay, okay.
Okay.
Now, what's a full-hole childhood was like that last 30 seconds.
How hard it would be for a child to feel calm, to feel safe,
to learn to trust anyone, and the lifelong impact that would have.
That makes me feel sad.
Ari only reacted the way he did, and recovered so quickly,
because the connection between him and his dad is usually so strong.
The positive relationships with the green ups in our lives gives kids the confidence we need.
To try new things, to explore, and be kid.
So please, try, remember, the most special period for our development is,
the first five years starting women's side and on these tiny.
What's something really impactful you can do?
Serve and return.
And when.
Early and often.
Please give it up for Amichot and Ari.
APPLAUSE
Every moment together is an opportunity to connect, talk and play.
Imagine the difference we could make if everyone everywhere did this.
To us, to children.
It's so much more than just again.
It's our future.
Thank you.
And say, Pittsburgh really can change the world.