How did you find me?
Oh, your hands are like ice.
You have to get you out of there.
No, I want you to leave this place.
Who's done this to you?
No time to explain.
You must go.
No.
I won't leave you.
You're doing here.
Help!
Who's there?
Who are you?
A master of this castle.
I've come from my father.
Please let him out.
Can't you see he's sick.
And he shouldn't have trespassed here.
But he could die.
Please, I'll do anything.
There's nothing you can do.
He's my prisoner.
Oh, there must be some way I can...
Wait.
Take me instead.
Who you?
You take his place.
No, no.
You don't know what you're doing.
If I did.
Would you let him go?
Yes.
But you must promise to stay here forever.
Come into the light.
No, Bill.
I won't let you do this.
You have my word.
Doug!
You see?
Dad?
It's hard to say.
Oh, I can't make out a heartbeat.
No, look.
He's breathing.
He's so big.
I'm not sure.
No, look.
He's breathing.
He's so beautiful.
So, uh, this is your first time in the marketplace, huh?
Is it that obvious?
Well, you do kind of stand out.
I mean, you don't seem to know how dangerous that go back can be.
I'm a fast learner.
Hmm.
Prepare to fight.
Did we die?
Did we die with honor?
Yeah.
Aim the candidates on you.
Faith, come back.
Help!
Come on.
Oh, I hate your back.
What am I doing right about now?
Quickly.
Come on.
We got to help.
You missed it.
How could you miss it?
Here now.
Don't do that.
Just hold still.
That hurts.
You'd hold still.
It wouldn't hurt as much.
If you hadn't run away, this wouldn't have happened.
If you hadn't frightened me, I wouldn't have run away.
Well, you shouldn't have been in the West Wing.
Well, you should learn to control your temper.
Now, hold still.
This might sting a little.
By the way, thank you for saving my life.
You won't.
If you kill him, you'll have to kill me too.
Daughter, stand back.
I won't.
I love him, Father.
Look around you.
This is where the path of hatred has brought us.
This is the path I choose, Father.
What will yours be?
My daughter speaks with a wisdom beyond her years.
We have all come here with anger in our hearts,
but she comes with courage and understanding me.
From this day forward, there is to be more killing.
That will not start with me.
Please.
Please, we'll go.
Whoa!
You should see a basis, because you're lucky.
What a thing, girls.
Come on, darling.
Jump!
Do you see them?
Yes!
Perfect!
Now we'll pull them to safe!
Hey!
Have a look!
I saw the lucky cricket!
We need help!
Oh, nice!
Very nice!
You can sit by me!
Oh!
We're going to die!
Okay, we're going to die!
No way we survived it!
There's the coming!
I let them slip through my fingers!
Come on!
And now we can do it!
You're the man!
Well, I saw that!
Step back, guys!
Give him some air!
Ping!
You are the craziest man I've ever met!
And for that, I owe you my life!
From now on, you have my trust!