Enjoy this extended snake peak at Disney's Mulan on Blu-ray and digital.
This way, that's the last one.
Gently.
Mulan, forget the chicken.
It will come back.
No!
Mulan, take control of yourself!
I'm not sure what I can do.
I can't get it.
Mulan, listen very carefully.
No!
Graceful!
Helagant!
Poiced.
From now.
these are the qualities we see in a good life these are the qualities we see in
mola with a wife serve her husband she must be silent
citizens we are under attack for northern invaders every family must
contribute one man to fight one man from every house one family
chin family do family whoa family I am hard job I serve the imperial army in
the last pair against the northern invaders have you no son old enough to fight I
am blessed with two daughters I will fight
loyal race and kill
Disney's Mulan on Blu-ray and digital rated PG-13