I just can't, this guy's awake. So I'm awake, so we have to play.
Go play by yourself!
Do you want to be a snowman?
Come on, come on, come on, come on!
Too much magic, too much magic!
This is amazing!
Watch the ass!
Hi, I'm Ookles! I'm Ookles!
I love you, Ookles!
Oh, sorry, yeah, I just find clothes restricting.
Bet you're wondering who we are and why we're here, it's really quite simple.
You began with two sisters, one boring with magical powers, one boring power less, their love of snowman, infinite.
I don't know, too high! Glass!
Oh, Mama Papa, help!
Slam, door shutting everywhere, sisters, torn apart!
Well, at least they have their parents, their parents are dead.
Oh, oh, oh, I'm on it! Oh, Mary, man, I just met!
I'm just gonna blow!
No, no, no!
Magic pulses through my snowflakes.
I live! Ice pallets for one! Ice pallets for one!
Get out, Anna!
Oh, my heart!
Oh, my goodness.
Only an act of true love can save you.
Here's a true love's kiss.
You're not worth it!
Yes, what? I'm the bad guy!
What?
An unfreeze step, forever.
Then she unfreezes.
Oh, and then Elsa woke up the magical spirits,
and we were forced out of our kingdom, now our only hope is to find the truth about the past,
but we don't have a clue how to do that, except Elsa's hearing voices, so we got that going for us.
Elsa!
Elsa, it's me, Anna.
Your sister, who didn't mean to make you freeze the summer?
I'm sorry, it's all my fault.
Of course none of it would have happened if she just told me her secret.
She's a stinker.
Oh, no, no, no, no, come back!
No, no, no, no!
Okay.
Get ready to jump, Sven!
You don't tell him what to do!
Hi! I do!
Jump, Sven!
But I just paid it off.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no!
Grab on!
Come on!
Pull, Sven, pull!
Whoa.
I'll replace your sled, and everything in it.
And I understand if you don't want to help me anymore.
Of course, I don't want to help her anymore.
In fact, this whole thing has ruined me for helping anyone ever again.
She'll die on her own.
I can live with that.
But you won't get your new sled if she's dead.
Sometimes I really don't like you.
Hold up!
We're coming!
Sure!
I mean, sure!
I'll let you tag along.
Anna, Elsa!
That time soon!
Uh-oh!
The princess is trapped in a snowball's evil spell!
Who elsea?
Make a princess!
A fancy one!
Oh no!
The princess trapped too!
Who cares about danger when there's love?
Anna!
Look!
She's sitting on the stage of the forest!
The lost fairies cry out!
Groove!
What time does the giraffe make?
Never mind.
They wait the fairies clean.
Who breaks the spell and saves everyone!
Where did you get that scarf?
That's a north-old giraffe.
What?
This is from one of our oldest families.
It was our mothers.
Well, Elsa, I see it.
It's mother.
Mother saved father's life that day.
Our mother was North Olga.
What?
I never knew winter could be so beautiful.
Yeah!
It really is beautiful isn't it?
It's so white!
You don't have a little color!
I'm thinking like maybe some crimson.
Are you sure true?
How about yellow?
No, not yellow.
Yellow and snow?
No, go.
Am I right?
Hi!
You're creepy.
Whoa!
Back at you.
Please don't tell me you want to just a hand.
No!
We got off to a bad start.
I knew you were the body!
Wait, what am I looking at right now?
Why are you hanging off the earth like a bat?
Wait one second.
Oh, thank you.
You're welcome.
Now I'm perfect.
Well, almost.
It was like my whole life that I've turned upside down.
Oh, whoa!
I'm sorry.
I've had her.
Are you okay?
Are you kidding me?
I am wonderful.
I've always wanted a nose.
It's like me being a unicorn.
Hey, whoa!
Oh, I love it even more.
All right, let's start this thing over.
Hi, everyone.
I'm all off.
And I like warm hugs.
All off?
That's right.
All off.
Oh.
Elsa?
It's me.
Anna.
Whoa!
Elsa?
It's me.
Anna.
Whoa.
Elsa, you look different.
It's a good difference.
And there's place.
It's amazing.
Thank you.
I never knew what I was capable of.
I love it.
I just want to see where I was going.
But I'm great.
Actually.
Prince Hans of the Southern Isles.
I love you.
I need to tell you about my past and where I'm from.
I'm listening.
I don't know.
What are you reading, Majesty?
I'll send you the English author.
Oh.