One moment.
You seem to be missing something.
This represents discipline.
And this represents strength.
You need both to reach the arrow.
We've got a long way to go.
Let's get down to clearness.
The hunt.
Did they send me daughters?
I am scared for sons.
Your saddest bunch I ever met.
But you can bat before and through.
Mr. Isle.
Make a man out of you.
Train will have a forest.
Come fire within.
Once you find your centre,
you are sure to end.
Your spine looks pale,
but they're not.
And you haven't got a clue.
Somehow I'll make a man.
I'm not out of you.
I'm never going to catch my breath.
Say goodbye to those who will never be.
I was at full in school for cutting jam.
Did the odds got them scared to death?
Hope you guys can see it right through me.
Now I really wish that I knew how to swim.
Your plan must be split down the course in river.
With all the force of the great time for you.
With all the strength of a raging fire.
The story is as the dark side of the moon.
Time is racing toward us.
Till the heart is alive.
Keep my air every order.
And you might survive.
You'll soon it for.
And the rage of war.
So pack up.
Go home as you're through.
How could I make a man out of you?
Your plan must be split down the course in river.
With all the force of the great time for you.
I'm never going to strike the raging fire.
The story is as the dark side of the moon.
Time must be split down the course in river.
With all the force of a great time for you.
With all the strength of a raging fire.
The story is as the dark side of the moon.
Happy Eye!
In the top right-hand corner of your screen.
The even more Disney Junior.
Where the magic begins.