what a happy happy day my little baby's good marriage
most you someone will hear you I can't help it you know dragons are very
emotional oh it seemed like just last month you and I were saving China it was
last month how time flies you know baby this must be a magical moment for you it's
It's not every day I get engaged.
No, I'm not telling me you're engaged.
After all, you know, I'm the guy that gave you
a pretty boy to hook up and my guardian or am I a guardian.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no, I ain't going out like this.
It's just me five hundred years to get this pedestal back
and I ain't about to give it up.
Hear me, you lazy, lounged lizard.
The moment Arboula is married, you've got your old job bank.
Remember, long duty.
Perhaps this will wring him out.
You have to go.
That's my cue to put operation, sharing and action.
Pretty boy is going to look so bad.
It'll send me line running for the hill.
This is going to be delicious.
Mm-hmm, mmm-hmm, watch this.
No!
I'm not sure.
Oh!
No!
Hey!
Hey, Steve!
drill!
Stay away!
Don't be crazy!
I regret you, officer.
Excuse me, you!
What's up?
Man, she laughed at your map, my map.
And if she's laughing to your face,
imagine what she's saying behind your back.
Back.
She's a loose cannon.
She's out of control.
I mean, who's in charge here?
You?
I'm in charge of life.
Ooh, life.
One!
Huh?
Oh.
Mm.
Hmm.
General shang.
Not it.
Hello with me, Mulan.
General shang.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Shang.
Oh, I got it.
General shang.
General.
Hearthead.
Oh.
Everything's got to have a strategy.
What?
The man won't brush his teeth without a backup plan.
Huh?
I believe myself.
I felt for those broad shoulders.
I didn't realize there wasn't much sitting on top of that.
Uh-huh.
Oh.
Except for that garlic breath.
Wait, that boy can peel paint.
Oops.
That's enough.
Very shit.
Hehehe.
I am good.