We have a new experience.
Yeah, aim the canon it's S
Hmm!
Jesus!
Oh!
Oh,ressage Emma, what in line they read about now?
Quickly quik- Ad crossover.
presidency!
Come on, we gotta help!
You missed it! How could you miss it was the dream made in progress?
Ok, we're gonna die! No way we survived this! This is coming!
I let this live to my fingers!
I know we can do it for you to man!
Well, sort of!
Step back, guys! Give us a man!
Ping? You are the craziest man I've ever met.
And for that, I owe you my life.
From now on, you have my trust.
Let's hear it for PING!
The bravest of us all!
Come on!
You took away!
You took away my victory!
No! I did!
The soldier from the mountains!
You don't have a plan!
Hey, I'm making this up.
Go!
No, shoot!
Wait ahead of you, sister! Come on, Kiki!
I need firepower!
Who are you?
You're a nightmare!
On the roof!
It looks like you're out of ideas.
Not quite.
Ready, Moshu?
I am ready, baby!
Like me!
Get off the roof!
You are a lucky boy!