What's your sign?
In Western astrology, it's a constellation determined by when your birthday falls in the
calendar.
But according to the Chinese zodiac, or shang shal, it's your shui shang, meaning the animal
assigned to your birth year.
And of the many myths explaining these animal signs and their arrangement, the most enduring
one is that of the great race.
As the story goes, U.D., or Jade Emperor, ruler of the heavens, wanted to devise a way to
measure time.
So he organized a race.
The first 12 animals to make it across the river would earn a spot on the zodiac calendar
in the order they arrived.
The rat rose with a sun to get an early start, but on the way to the river he met
the horse, the tiger, and the ox.
As the rat was small and couldn't swim very well, he asked the bigger animals for help.
While the tiger and horse refused, the kind-hearted ox agreed to carry the rat across.
Yet, just as they were about to reach the other side, the rat jumped off the ox's head
and secured first place.
The ox came in second, with a powerful tiger right behind him.
The rabbit, two smalls to battle the current, nimbly hopped across stones and logs to come
in fourth.
The horse came the dragon, who could have flown directly across, but stopped to help some
creatures she had encountered on the way.
After her came the horse, galloping across the river, but just as she got across, the snakes
thither by.
The startled horse reared back, letting the snake sneak into sixth place.
The Jade Emperor looked out at the river and spotted the sheep, the monkey, and the rooster,
all atop a raft, working together to push it through the weeds.
When they made it across, the tree or agreed to give eighth place to the sheep, who had
been the most comforting and harmonious of them, followed by the monkey and the rooster.
Next came the dog, scrambling onto the shore.
He was a great swimmer, but froliced in the water for so long that he only managed to
come in eleventh.
The final spot was claimed by the pig, who had gotten hungry and stopped to eat in
nap, before finally waddling across the finish line.
And so, each year is associated with one of the animals in this order, with the cycle
starting over every 60 years.
Why 60 and not 12?
Well, the traditional Chinese calendar is made up of two overlapping systems.
The animals of the zodiac are associated with what's called the 12 earthly branches, or
shaar, dijin.
Another system, the ten heavenly stems, or shiqingan, is linked with the five classical
elements of metal, dijin, wood, moo, water, shi, fire, hoa, and earth, tool.
Each element is assigned yin or yang, creating a ten-year cycle.
When the twelve animals of the earthly branches are matched with the five elements, plus
the yin or the yang of the heavenly stems, it creates 60 years of different combinations,
known as a six-aginary cycle, or gangju.
So someone born in 1980 would have the sign of young metal monkey, while someone born
in 2007 would be yin fire pick.
In fact, you can also have an inner animal based on your birth month, a true animal
based on your birth date, and a secret animal based on your birth hour.
It was the great race that supposedly determined which animals were enshrined in the Chinese
zodiac, but as the system spread through Asia, other cultures made changes to reflect
their communities.
So if you consult the Vietnamese zodiac, you may discover that you're a cat, not a rabbit.
And if you're in Thailand, a mythical snake called anaga replaces the dragon.
So whether or not you play stock and what the zodiac says about you as an individual,
it certainly reveals much about the culture it comes from.