The following contains clips from Disney's tangled beauty and the beast.
No one, the little mermaid, and no one.
Now available on Blu-ray and DVD.
Rapunzel?
Rapunzel, what's going on up there?
Are you all right?
I know I was princess.
Please speak up, Rapunzel. You know how I hate the mumbling.
I am the lost princess.
Aren't I?
Did I mumble?
Mother?
Or should I even call you that?
Rapunzel, do you even hear yourself?
Why would you ask such a ridiculous question?
It was you! It was all you!
Everything I did was to protect you.
Rapunzel spends my entire life hiding from people who would use me for my power.
Rapunzel, when I should have been hiding from you!
Where will you go? He won't be there for you?
What did you do to him?
That criminal is to be hanged for his crimes.
No, no, it's all right. Listen to me.
All of this is as it should be.
No, you were wrong about the world, and you were wrong about me.
And I will never let you use my hair again!
Ow!
Belle, it's all right, Papa. I'm home.
I thought I'd never see you again.
I missed you so much.
But the beast, how did you escape?
I didn't escape, Papa.
Hey, let me go.
That horrible beast!
But he's different, now, Papa. He's changed somehow.
Hi!
A still away.
Hello, dear little fella.
You didn't think I'd see you again?
Belle, why'd you go away? Don't you like us anymore?
Oh, Chip. Of course I do. It's just them.
May I help you?
I've come to collect your father.
My father.
Don't worry about it myself.
We'll take good care of him.
My father's not crazy.
He was raving like a lunatic.
We all heard him didn't we?
No, I won't let you.
Marries, tell us again, oh man.
Just how big was the beast?
He was, he was enormous.
I'd say at least eight.
No, more like 10 feet.
You don't get much crazier than that.
It's true, I tell you.
Get him out of here.
Call me.
No, you can't do this.
Poor Belle.
Wait, it's a shame about your father.
You know he's not crazy, Gaston?
Mmm, I might be able to clear up this little misunderstanding.
If, if you marry me.
What?
One little word, Belle, that's all it takes.
Never.
Have it your way.
Now, you come, come out of me.
My father's not crazy and I can prove it.
Show me the beast.
No!
You should danger us.
No, no, he never heard anyone.
Please, I know he looks vicious, but he's really kind and gentle.
He's my friend.
If I didn't know better, I'd think you had feelings for this monster.
He's no monster, Gaston.
You are.
She really does love him, doesn't she, Sebastian?
Well, it's like I always say you're majesty.
Children got to be free.
Read their own life.
You'll always say that.
Oh, then I guess there's just one problem left.
And what's that, you're majesty?
How much I'm going to miss her.
OK.
Yes.
Ten.
I
Was this close
This close to impressing the ancestors getting the top shelf and entourage
Man, oh my fine work
Hi, I
Should never have left home
Come on you want to save your father's life who knew you'd end up shaming him and disgracing your ancestors and losing all your friends
You know, you just gotta get learned and let these things go
Maybe I didn't go for my father
Maybe what I really wanted was to prove I could do things right
So when I looked in the mirror I
See someone worthwhile
But I was wrong. I see nothing
Well, that's just cuz this needs a little spit that's all
Yeah, me shatters up points I
Can see you look easy like so pretty
The truth is we're both roads your ancestors never said me they don't even like me
I mean you risk your life to help people you love I wish your life to help myself
And leave you had good intentions
But what do you mean you're not lucky you lied to me?
And what are you a sheep
I
Have to face my father sooner or later
Let's go home. Yeah
This ain't gonna be pretty, but don't you worry, okay?
Things work out
You started this name together and that's how we'll finish you I
promise
Oh
Whatever just happened
Lay me not in the peak. Oh, Grandma
Oh
Are you gonna talk dad? I miss mom. I don't have to tell him anything
He was right
About going out there
It's time to put my stone on the mountain
Oh
Okay, well then head on back
Put that stone up there
Why aren't you trying to talk me out of it you said that's what you wanted it is
When I die I'm going to come back as one of these
Or I chose the wrong tattoo. Why are you acting weird? I'm the village crazy lady. That's my job
If there's something you want to tell me just tell me
Is there something you want to tell me is there something you want to hear?
You've been told all our people stories, but what?
Why it is this place do you really think our ancestors stayed within the reef?