Anna, I think we should go.
No, I'm not leaving without you, Elsa.
Yes, you are.
Stop!
What a stop!
Go away!
Ah!
Heads up!
No!
Watch out for my butt!
It is not nice to throw people.
asso!
Whoa, whoa!
Fight, stay alive.
Relax, just come down!
Calm down.
OK.
Just let the casting go.
Great.
OK, come on.
See, now you made a mad.
I'll distract him.
You guys go.
OK, Bree?
No, no, no.
Stop.
Put your cuttle on harder.
Jim, I'm having a good one!
I need them.
What is wrong with me?
Man, am I out of shape?
Man, where'd you guys go?
We totally lost marshmallow back there.
Hey, we were just talking about you.
All good things?
No!
This is not making much of a difference, is it?
All good things?
No!
This is not making much of a difference, is it?
Whoa!
Hey, get in there, guys!
So go faster!
Wait, what?
Whoa!
Don't go back!
We won't!
Whoa!
Uhm...
The queen!
I got that in me...
aaaah!
Ugh...
show yourself right now
ialsa, do you?
Oh I will momma I will
elseus dud
Oh, that's dead on a prize.
And then a bunch of important things happen that I forgot,
but all that matters is I was right and water has memory,
and thus, I live in so deep.
Oh, we live.
We live.
Yeah.
Good smell, yeah.